Mhamad Raad

Full-stack Engineer (FE-Focused) | Front-end Engineer | React

Motivated, software engineer with **1+ years of experience** versed in pair programming, communication, and time management skills. Eager to develop projects using **React**, **Next**, **or Remix** which help people and enhance technologies. Throughout my past studies and experiences, I have gained the needed soft and technical skills to be a valuable asset to any team, and am eager to take my soft and technical skills to the next level.

EXPERIENCE

Gateway for ICT Solutions, Erbil

Internship - Front-end web developer

October 2022 - April 2023

- Integrating payment functionality into the website through APIs.
- Developing a responsive and pixel-perfect user interface using Sass, and React.
- Achieved 80% test coverage on the developed components using jest and RTL.
- Collaborate in a scrum environment to achieve success through communication.

MICROVERSE, Remote

Volunteer - Mentor

August 2022 - April 2023

- Mentored 2 junior developers, providing technical support through code reviews.
- Proposed improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance through pull requests.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE, Remote

Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

August 2022 - April 2023

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development.
- Developing projects using Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux, following TDD, and other methodologies.
- Developed skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups as an agile (scrum) habitant.
- Communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

(UTM) The University of Technology Malaysia,

September 2019 - March 2023

Bachelor, Software Engineering

- CGPA: 3.4.
- Each semester we had to build various projects with different frameworks and languages such as (Pharmacy e-shop: (JSP, servlet, and Java Bean), We Assist: (Flutter), e-Learning: (Flutter), Moisture Detecto: (C++, Arduino), Fast-Food: (PHP)).

Software Projects

FIB Shop | Github

e-commerce platform showcasing Gateway's FIB Payment integration for buying products online, (React, Context, Sass, Jest, rest API, ES6).

Trip Reservation | Github

Microverse graduation project, (React, Redux, Jest, Ruby on Rails, Rspec, JWT).

Order Meals | Github

The project was built with (Context, Firebase, and React).

hamaraad883@gmail.com <u>GitHub | LinkedIn |</u> <u>Portfolio</u>

SKILLS

Front-end - Proficient
React | Next | Remix
Redux | Context | Sass
Bootstrap | REST API |
JSON | JavaScript | ES6

Front-end - Moderate

React Three Fiber |
Fiber/Drei | React
Transition Group | jQuery
Jest | React Testing Lib
TypeScript | Tailwind |
Material UI| Framer
motion | eslinters

Back-end - Proficient
PostgreSQL | MySQL

Back-end - Moderate Rspec | Ruby | Node.js Express | Ruby on Rails

Tools & Methods

Git | GitHub | Netlify Vercel | Render | TDD Mobile First Approach Chrome Dev Tools | Agile (Scrum) | Firebase MongoDB | Figma | Jira Postman | NPM | Yarn Trello | Webpack | CI/CD Code Reviews

Professional

Remote | Management Pair-Programming Teamwork | Mentoring

Languages

English: Proficient. Kurdish: Native. Arabic: Intermediate.